Seth Greenbaum

Denver, CO

(410) 917-4427

sethmgreenbaum@gmail.com

Offering experience in molecular biology, food science, and IT, in both laboratory research and industrial manufacturing contexts, as well as a focus on the application of scientific methods into product design, product testing, quality assurance, process improvement and automation.

Education/Certification

Bachelor of Arts in Biology: Oberlin College, Oberlin, OH Spring 2013

University of Denver Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp, Certificate Spring 2020

American Society of Plant Biologists, member since 2014

MED Key Badge

Work Experience

Green Chef/Hello Fresh: Boulder, CO 2015 - current position -Process and Industrial Engineer, Department of Automation and Engineering:

Provided scientific technical support for innovation and continuous improvement in the fields of organic produce and home meal kit delivery; designed testing programs for packaged produce and new shipping technology; pursued cost savings through implementing food processing and pack line automation and data-handling equipment; built analytical and reporting tools for monitoring production processes; determined guidelines for produce handling through shelf studies and microbiological tests;

<u>Dept. of Biology, Oberlin College: Oberlin, OH, 2013-2014</u> -Research technician: Managed Plant Molecular Biology Laboratory of Dr. Marta Laskowski, conducted and presented research on organ development in *Arabidopsis thaliana*, assisted undergraduate student research

Student Academic Services, Oberlin College:, Oberlin, OH, 2012-2013 - Biology Tutor

Campus Dining Services, Oberlin College: Oberlin, OH, 2010-2013 -Food Service Worker.

Dept. of Chemistry, Oberlin College: Oberlin, OH 2011-2012 -Chemistry Stockroom Assistant:

<u>Yaffa Catering:</u>, <u>Baltimore</u>, <u>MD 2008-2009</u> -Kitchen and Commissary Worker:

Wilmer Eye Institute: Johns Hopkins University Baltimore, MD 2008 -Summer IT Assistant:

Volunteer Experience

<u>Oberlin Student Cooperative Association, Oberlin, OH 2010-2011</u> -Dinner Head Cook:

<u>Wilmer Eye Institute Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore MD 2012</u> -Research Intern: in the Laboratory of Dr. Debasish Sinha and Dr. Malika Valapala, assisted in research on autophagy processes in a potential model for Macular Degeneration

<u>Wilmer Eye Institute Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD 2006, 2007</u> -Research Intern: In the Laboratory of Dr, Elia Duh, learned molecular biology techniques and aided research

Technical Skills

Microsoft Office, Google Suite, Google Apps Script, HTML, CSS, Python, JavaScript, R, SPSS, MATLAB, MaxMSP, Adobe Suite

Publications and Presentations

Valapala M, Wilson C, Hose S, Bhutto IA, Grebe R, Dong A, Greenbaum S, Gu L, Sengupta S, Cano M, et al. Lysosomal- mediated waste clearance in retinal pigment epithelial cells is regulated by CRYBA1/β A3/A1-crystallin via V-ATPase- MTORC1 signaling. Autophagy 2014; 10:85 - 101: PMID: 24468901:

Greenbaum S, Du Y, Laskowski M, "COI1 dependent and COI1 independent mechanisms of Lateral Root Positioning". Poster presented at American Society of Plant Biologists Midwest Section Meeting 2014 March 22-23; Columbus, Ohio